# **Syed Hasnain Bukhari**

## Bangkok



#### About

Full Stack Developer with 5+ years of rich professional experience of building and delivering highly scalable, enterprise grade software products. I hold a Bachelor's degree in Computer Sciences from the Punjab University College of Information Technology, Lahore, Pakistan

**Phone:** (+66) 630789575. (+92) 3017924305 **Email:** syedhasnainbukhari01@hotmail.com

## **Work Experience**

## Agoda

#### Full Stack Software Engineer

2021 - Present

Leading several teams, working on solutions based upon distributed computing to make the e-commerce scene under the global travel space alive

- Working with teams to migrate long-running legacy systems to a newer and a better stack
- Keeping track of the learning abilities of my team so that they can progress in their respective careers and interests
- Having 1:1s to shape up the team culture and align them with essential matters at the organization
- Build a mindset and culture of quality first; Owning our stuff and converting them to quality artefacts and systems
- Help the organization envision what moving away from legacy could mean and preach the benefits within the team(s)
  Help the team understand Agility at work and take them through ceremonies: This helps the team give their best
- Help the team understand Agility at work and take them through ceremonies; This helps the team give their best following sprints
- Making an effort around organizational values, so it lives within the team and work we do.

## Strategic System International

#### Senior Software Engineer

2019 - 2021

Design and developed multiple major modules and provide technical support to web application as well mobile application. My responsibilities include:

- Building micro services oriented systems that enable integration with various external systems.
- Working in an agile, scrum environment using .NET stack to design and build highly optimized solutions to be deployed at a global scale.
- Optimizing and refactoring existing modules to accommodate new functionality and enhance performance and maintainability.
- Design and develop timesheets management module based on types of systems. User can track workings hours and working experience with different clients. User can upload paper timesheets as well.
- Implementation of Elastic search to enhance the performance and visualize the data.

- Provide technical to mobile application
- Provide technical support and consultancy to other projects as well

#### CureMD

#### **Software Engineer**

2017 - 2019

Developed multiple major projects, as a full stack .NET developer as well as a software architect. My responsibilities include:

- Building highly scalable and robust, service-oriented systems that enable integration of our flagship product with various external information exchange partners.
- Working in an agile, scrum environment using .NET stack to design and build highly optimized solutions to be deployed at a global scale.
- Providing technical and client support to various deployed products. Co-ordinate and plan inter and intra team activities.
- Restructure and refactor modules of existing products to accommodate new functionality and enhance performance and maintainability.

## **Logix Infinity**

#### **Software Engineer**

2016 - 2017

Worked as a software developer, specializing in web and desktop application development, mainly using the .NET stack along with other web technologies (Angular, Ionic and JavaScript). It gave me a chance to work on an array of diverse projects, offering me a great learning experience and exposure. I've developed web-based software using ASP.NET (MVC, WEB API, .NetCore), Angular/Ionic and SQLServer.

#### Education

#### **FAST - NUCES**

#### Computer Science, Bachelor

2006 - 2010

#### Skills

#### Web Engineering

- Software Architecture
- Development and Troubleshooting
- Project Management & Coordination

### • Software Architecture

- Design-patterns
- o Distributed systems

- Scalability
- Maintainability

## • Software Development

- Sustainability
- Portability
- Scalability
- Reasonability

## • Programming Languages

- C#
- o C++

#### • Web Programming

- ASP.NET
- (Web Form, MVC, .Net Core, Nhibernate, Entity Framework, ADO.NET, Web API, WCF and WPF),
- Micro services
- Elastic Search
- Javascript/JQuery,
- HTML/CSS

#### Reports

- Crystal Reports
- JSReports

#### Reports

- MS SQL
- PostgreSQL
- SQLLite
- MongoDB

#### References

Amir is surely missed by his team/peers and I think any company would find great benefit with the addition of Amir to their leadership and technical team. Wish you all the best Amir and hope our paths cross again. - **Heinrich Rust** 

As a colleague Amir is friendly, personable, has an easy manner and great sense of humour. A clear communicator with a voice for radio, Amir is wise head on young shoulders. - **Paul Fitzgerald**